Jenaro Calviño

Cordoba, Argentina

LinkedIn | Github | jen.calvineo@gmail.com

ABOUT ME

I have over six years of experience working as a front-end engineer and more than five years as a remote employee with a great track record of deliverability.

For the past three and a half years I've written hundreds of Typescript PRs for the Disney+ streaming service and others in the Disney family such as Hulu and ESPN+, used by millions of users across the globe.

EXPERIENCE

Frontend Engineer Remote

Disney (@Hypergiant)

2021-present

2020-2021

- Led the efforts to unify and migrate the customer activations feature while adding value with the newer HBO max partnership.
- Developed a developer tool that communicated with the third party activations API and allowed both developers and testers to streamline the activations testing process.
- Took ownership of a legacy in-house analytics library, refactored and maintained it for more than 100 peers to use.
- Wrote a command line interface tool to avoid manually updating the configurations of 132 countries, taking the time of a gruesome two-hour task to a minute.

Frontend Developer Remote

Airfleet

- Developed pixel-perfect websites using Gatsby.
- Fixed and improved scroll animations, increasing load time and lighthouse scores and overall SEO ranking.

Frontend Developer

CraCSS

Remote
2019-2020

- Developed the company's marketing website while learning Svelte.
- Led the frontend efforts on a user-facing product to make church seat reservations during the pandemic.

Full Stack DeveloperCordoba, ArgentinaCordoba Experts2018-2019

REFERENCES

Alfonso Cornejo | Lead Software Engineer Wanying Xu | Engineering Manager

Disney

alfunkso@outlook.com wfejob@gmail.com

SKILLS

Programming Languages: Typescript, JavaScript, React, Next.js, Remix

EDUCATION

National University of Cordoba, Argentina

2013-2017